Faculty Council fonds
Simon Fraser University Archives and Records Management Department
Faculty Council fonds
1965 - 1973
F-112
25 cm of textual records
Simon Fraser University Archives and Records Management Department Maggie Benston Student Services Building, Rm. 0400 8888 University Dr. Burnaby British Columbia Canada V5A 1S6 Telephone: 778.782.3805 Email: archives@sfu.ca http://www.sfu.ca/archives
Faculty Council
The Universities Act, 1963, c. 52, s. 25 provided for a Faculty Council from each of British Columbia's three universities. Membership included the President as Chairman, the Registrar as secretary, the Librarian, the Deans and at least five faculty members. The Faculty Council was granted several powers (Universities Act, s. 61) including making rules and regulations with respect to student discipline, and approving the establishment of a representative student government.
SFU's Faculty Council, established in 1965, consisted of the officials listed above and 6 faculty members (2 elected from each of the original faculties of Arts, Science, and Education). One of its earliest actions was to examine the proposed constitution of the Simon Fraser Student Society in order to facilitate the formal recognition of the SFSS. In addition, it studied the issue of a separate graduate student society. The Council established policies in such areas as library fines, traffic violations, and conduct in student residences. It also heard individual disciplinary cases involving students accused of misconduct such as cheating and plagiarism. The last minutes of the Faculty Council are from 1973. The revised Universities Act in 1974 did not provide for the continuation of the Council.
published
Full
Revised
Title of the fonds is based on the name of its creator.
Fonds consists of records documenting the functions and activities of the Faculty Council. Fonds includes agendas, minutes, correspondence, policies and procedures, and other documents.
The agendas, minutes, and papers were refoldered and kept as maintained by the Registrar in reverse chronological order in a binder. The file, "Miscellaneous Supporting Papers," was also received from the Registrar, who had intended to add these documents to the committee binder. One file, containing corresondence about a proposed graduate student society, was compiled by former archives staff. It was added to the fonds for its informational value.
The records were transferred to the Archives from the Registrar, who was the Secretary of the Council.
All accessions have been processed as of September 2002. No further accruals are expected.
Please consult the records of the Senate Committee to Consider Student Academic Discipline and Conduct, F-84-1-10.
Some files may contain personal or confidential information. Access to these files may be restricted as required by law. Files marked 'pending review' must be reviewed by an archivist prior to release, and as a result of the review access restrictions may apply. Please see the file lists and consult the archivist for more details.
File list is available.
- Faculty Council files, 1965 - 1973; F-112-1; 25 cm of textual records
  published
  Some files may contain personal or confidential information. Access to these files may be restricted as required by law. Files marked 'pending review' must be reviewed by an archivist prior to release, and as a result of the review access restrictions may apply. Please see the file lists and consult the archivist for more details.
  - Agendas, minutes and papers, 1965; F-112-1-0-0-1 (Archival box - standard 112-1)
    Textual records
    Pending review
  - Agendas, minutes and papers, 1966; F-112-1-0-0-2 (Archival box - standard 112-1)
  - Agendas, minutes and papers, 1966; F-112-1-0-0-3 (Archival box - standard 112-1)
  - Agendas, minutes and papers, 1966; F-112-1-0-0-4 (Archival box - standard 112-1)
  - Agendas, minutes and papers, 1967 - 1968; F-112-1-0-0-5 (Archival box - standard 112-1)
  - Agendas, minutes and papers, 1972; F-112-1-0-0-6 (Archival box - standard 112-1)
  - Agendas, minutes and papers, 1973; F-112-1-0-0-7 (Archival box - standard 112-2)
  - Information items including special cases, 1966 - 1972; F-112-1-0-0-8 (Archival box - standard 112-2)
  - Faculty Council cross reference index, A-M, 1965 - 1972; F-112-1-0-0-9 (Archival box - standard 112-2)
  - Faculty Council cross reference index, N-Z, 1965 - 1972; F-112-1-0-0-10 (Archival box - standard 112-2)
  - Faculty Council miscellaneous supporting papers, 1965 - 1973; F-112-1-0-0-11 (Archival box - standard 112-2)
  - Faculty Council correspondence re Graduate Students' Association, 1967 - 1968; F-112-1-0-0-12 (Archival box - standard 112-2)